Guide to the Olin Library Circulation Department Records, 1947-1985.
Olin Library Circulation Department Records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Olin Library Circulation Department records, 1947-1985.
13-5-2086
Cornell University. Libraries. John M. Olin Library. Circulation Dept.
6 cubic ft.
Reports, policies, records, meeting minutes, tally sheets, manuals, evaluations.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records and material pertaining to Olin Library and various other libraries on the Cornell University campus.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes material pertaining to FAUL (Five Associated University Libraries), CULSA (Cornell University Libraries Staff Association), the Committee on Economic Status of Librarians, South Central Research Library Council, the Olin Library Reference and Technical Services Departments; automation of library functions, particularly circulation; reclassification of library materials; memoranda and reports of the Academic Assembly; procedures and policies of the Acquisitions Department; records of various libraries on campus; and memoranda, minutes, shelving tally sheets, personnel manuals, job descriptions, evaluations, tour information, monthly reports, minutes of department staff meetings, 1974-1984; and other records of the Olin Library Circulation Department.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Cornell University Libraries Staff Association.; Cornell University. Libraries. John M. Olin Library. Acquisitions Dept.; Cornell University. Libraries. John M. Olin Library. Reference Dept.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Records of the Olin Library Circulation Department
  - Cornell University and University of Rochester Circulation Automation Study, 1967; 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cornell University and University of Rochester Circulation Study, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Review Board for Work Progress of Student Assistants at Olin Circulation, Nov. 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Olin Kibrary Coinfax Report Sheets, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Constituent Assembly Matters, 1956; 1968,; 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Five Associated University Libraries (FAUL), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Five Associated University Libraries (FAUL), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Five Associated University Libraries (FAUL), 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Five Associated University Libraries (FAUL), 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Five Associated University Libraries (FAUL), Harper College, 1966-1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Five Associated University Libraries (FAUL), State University of New York at Buffalo, 1969-1970; 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Five Associated University Libraries (FAUL), Rochester, 1968-1970; 1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Five Associated University Libraries (FAUL), Syracuse, 1968-1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Colorado Instrument's Ciculation Systems, 1971; 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Automation Policies of Libraries, A-L, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Automation Policies of Libraries, M-Z. Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, 1959; 1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Cornell University Circulation Department (Including Flow Sheets), 1960; 1963-1965,; 1978 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Circulation Committee - Minutes and Agenda of Readers Services, 1961-1966 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Shelving Tally Sheets, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Shelving Tally Sheets, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Shelving Tally Sheets, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Shelving Tally Sheets, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Shelving Tally Sheets, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Shelving Tally Sheets, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Shelving Tally Sheets, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Shelving Tally Sheets, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Shelving Tally Sheets, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Shelving Tally Sheets, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Shelving Tally Sheets, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Shelving Tally Sheets, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Shelving Tally Sheets, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Shelving Tally Sheets, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Shelving Tally Sheets, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Academic Assembly Memos and Reports, 1971-1975; 1981 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Committee on Economic Status of Librarians, 1971-1981 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Cornell University Libraries Staff Association (CULSA), 1971-1975 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Acquisitions Department, Procedures and Policies, 1968-1978 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - South Central Research Library Council, 1969-1975 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Circulation Department Minutes, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Circulation Department Minutes, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Circulation Department Minutes, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Circulation Department Minutes, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Circulation Department Minutes, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Circulation Department Minutes, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Circulation Department Minutes, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Circulation Department Minutes, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Circulation Department Minutes, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Circulation Department Minutes, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Trial Communication Notebook, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Trial Communication Notebook, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Trial Communication Notebook, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Printing costs, record keeping, circulation control control system, McBee Keysort system, 1947-1974 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Technical Services of Cornell University Libraries - Meetings of Department Heads and Designated Assistants, 1961-1981 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Reorganization of Technical Services, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Circulation Department - Student Employees Personnel Manuals, Guides and Job Descriptions, 1965; 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Circulation Department - Student Employees' Manual, Drafts of and Printed Copies, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Memos, Evaluations, Procedures re Circulation Department Student Assistants, 1956-1980 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Olin Library Tour Information, Data Information on Cornell University Libraries, 1965-1975 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Reclassification Project, 1956; 1958-1958,; 1978 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Committee Reports, 1971; 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Information on Photo-copy machines, 1964-1981 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Olin/Uris Department Heads and Designated Assistants, Minutes of Meetings, 1950-1954; 1957-1959 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Olin/Uris Department Heads and Designated Assistants, Minutes of Meetings, 1960-1964 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Olin/Uris Department Heads and Designated Assistants, Minutes of Meetings, 1965-1969 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Olin/Uris Department Heads and Designated Assistants, Minutes of Meetings, 1970-1975 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Olin/Uris Department Heads and Designated Assistants, Minutes of Meetings, 1976-1980 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Cornell University Interlibrary Loan, 1964-1965; 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Policies and Procedures for Selection, Processing, Storage and Reporting of Microfilms, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Scheduling, Including Vacation Requests, 1968-1977 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Cornell University Libraries Planning Council, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Missing Books, 1959-1979 (Box 3, Folder 70a)
- Department Libraries
  - Engineering Library, Carpenter Hall, 1974; 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Graduate School of Buisness and Public Administration, Eastwick Library, Malott Hall, 1969-1971; 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Fine Arts Library, 1969; 1972 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Albert R. Mann Librbary, New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, New York State College of Human Ecology, 1976-1981 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Music Library, Lincoln Hall, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Physical Sciences Library, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Uris Library, 1962-1974 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Olin Library, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Dormitory Library Collection, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Africana Studies and Research Center Library, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Statler Club Library, 1963; 1966,; 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Administrative Services Department, 1961; 1963,; 1972,; 1975 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Conference Rooms, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Commercial Use Reproduction of Cornell University Libraries' Property, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Records of stolen or lost books returned to the Cornell Libraries by purchasers at an auction, Oct. 16, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Minutes of Public Service Meetings, 1961-1965 (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - Minutes of Public Service Meetings, 1967-1973 (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - Minutes of Public Service Meetings, 1974-1981 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Minutes of the Circulation Subcommittees of Reader Services Group, 1962-1975 (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Reference Department, 1964; 1969-1975 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Information on other library systems outside of Cornell, 1954-1974 (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Checkout Tally Sheets, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - Checkout Tally Sheets, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Checkout Tally Sheets, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Checkout Tally Sheets, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Checkout Tally Sheets, 195 (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - Circulation Department Monthly Reports, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - Circulation Deaprtment Monthly Reports, Jan. 1981-June 1981 (Box 4, Folder 98)
  - Circulation Department Monthly Reports, July 1981-Dec. 1981 (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Circulation Department Monthly Reports, Jan. 1981-June 1981 (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - Unprocessed Material (Box 5)
  - Unprocessed Material (Box 6)